Contact

acontursi@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/acontursi (LinkedIn) www.indicadordemocratico.com (Company) www.adriancontursi.com.ar (Blog)

Top Skills

Data Science
Data Analysis
Research

Languages

Russian (Elementary)
French (Professional Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Publications

Segmentación estratégica multinivel: el caso de Santa Fe en las elecciones 2017

Informe del Observatorio sobre la Democracia en las Américas: Pandemia / 2021

La dinámica de la competencia políticapartidaria santafecina entre 2007 y 2015: ¿realineamiento partidario y estabilidad regional del voto?

Comportamiento de las cuentas oficiales de Twitter de los candidatos a Diputados Nacionales por Santa Fe durante el debate televisivo 2017

Concepción del Estado y cambios organizaciones en la provincia de Santa Fe (2007 a 2013)

Adrian Contursi-Reynoso

Political and Data Scientist | Associate Professor | GIS Developer Santa Fe, Santa Fe, Argentina

Summary

I am a Political and Data Scientist who is passionate about the academic goal to pursue new knowledge. Because of that, I combine Political and Data Analysis with Computing. This allows me to build a strong background in Statistic and Geographic Information Systems.

I have a demonstrated history of more than 15 years of leading projects in the Public Sector, and more than 7 years in the Academic sector, teaching and researching.

I have also been working as Consultant for international organizations which offer me the possibility to grow my skills in Collaboration, Adaptability, Negotiation, Solve problem and Leading.

I am currently seeking new challenges and opportunities, so if you would like to work together, contact me.

Experience

Universidad Autónoma de Entre Ríos 5 years 10 months

Associate Professor of Applied Statistics March 2022 - Present (11 months)

Associate Professor at Social Research June 2020 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Associate Professor at Political Geography May 2019 - Present (3 years 9 months) Paraná. Entre Ríos

Associate Professor at Geography of the Capitalist Globalization of the Nation States

April 2017 - Present (5 years 10 months)

Paraná, Entre Ríos, Argentina

Universidad Nacional del Litoral Assistant Professor at Political Geography and Electoral Geography June 2016 - Present (6 years 8 months)

Santa Fe, Argentina

Gobierno de la Provincia de Santa Fe 17 years 5 months

Chief of Division.

September 2018 - Present (4 years 5 months)

Santa Fe, Argentina

Head of Technical Division.

February 2013 - September 2018 (5 years 8 months)

Santa Fe, Argentina

I am responsible for the development of the SiGI (Integral Management System) for the General Direction of Programming at DPV. This include internal coordination and coordination with other divisions and governmental organism.

I work together with the Planning Direction to upgrade the Vial Inventory, we georeference trace and objects to update it. This include data collection in fieldwork and post process to obtain geographical objects compatible with international norms and standards (ISO 19100, 19115, 19139 e ISO/TC 211).

I am the nexus between the DPV and other governmental organism. I represent the DPV in front of the National Comission of Spatial Activities, where I advise to acquire products from satellite images. Also, I am part of a special commission between the DPV and the Cadastre Service and Land Information, where we update the geographic information which affect physical, legal and economically the properties in the province.

Programmer.

September 2005 - January 2013 (7 years 5 months)

Santa Fe, Argentina

Organización de los Estados Americanos 9 months

Independent Consultant

April 2022 - December 2022 (9 months)

Network Studies for the Reduction of Polarization and Conflict.

Based on the selection of eight Latin American countries, a study was carried out on the impact of affective polarization on Social Networks.

An algorithm was created that made it possible to measure, together with the visualization and analysis of social networks, the evolution of polarization at the national level. As well as identifying relevant issues and actors that could contribute to reducing the existing polarization.

Independent Consultant

May 2022 - August 2022 (4 months)

Support for the consolidation of the Democracy Observatory.

Contribute to the preparation of the document on Democracy in the Americas.

Chapter 2: Democracy Observatory: indicators on the political, economic and social impact of the pandemic.

* It was supported in the elaboration and calculations of the indicators and indices of the chapter.

Chapter 3: Trends that may affect the effective exercise of democracy.

* The sections on "Political polarization, political fanaticism, hate speech and its effects on governance" and "Viral democracy, social networks, disinformation and fake news" were developed.

Organización de los Estados Americanos External Consultant December 2018 - January 2019 (2 months)

Political and Social Network Analysis.

Organización de los Estados Americanos Intern

January 2017 - April 2017 (4 months)

Washington D.C. Metro Area

To contribute to the development of methodologies for the quantitative analysis of data extracted from the monitoring of open sources of information, building on the basis of the OAS Americas Digital Information System (ADIS) Implement at least one social network monitoring and analysis pilot in electoral context (Ecuador / Honduras MOE).

Collaborate with knowledge management for situational analysis, design and construction of databases and compilation of relevant documents (eSAPEM). Support political analysis efforts, providing inputs for briefings in response to emerging needs.

Document methodological contributions, providing to institutional memory and the sustainability of political analysis efforts.

Concordia Language Villages Credit Teacher June 2013 - July 2013 (2 months)

Marine on Saint Croix, MN

Middlebury College

Teacher at Middlebury-Monterey Language Academy June 2011 - July 2011 (2 months)

Bristol, RI

MMLA at Roger Williams University

Middlebury College

Teacher at Middlebury-Monterey Language Academy June 2010 - July 2010 (2 months)

Great Barrington, MA

MMLA at Bard College at Simon's Rock

Concordia Language Villages

Credit Teacher

June 2006 - July 2006 (2 months)

Marine on Saint Croix, MN

ELdB at Wilder Foundation

Concordia Language Villages

Credit Teacher

June 2005 - August 2005 (3 months)

Marine on Sait Croix, MN

ELdB at Wilder Foundation

Concordia Language Villages

Credit Teacher

June 2004 - August 2004 (3 months)

Marine on Saint Croix, MN

ELdB at Wilder Foundation

Concordia Language Villages

Senior Counselor

June 2003 - July 2003 (2 months)

Oak Hills, MN

ELdB at Oak Hills

Education

Universidad Nacional de Rosario

Master's Degree, Integration and International Cooperation, International Relations and Affairs · (2014 - 2016)

University of Oxford

Annenberg-Oxford Media Policy Summer Institute, Communication and Media Studies · (2018 - 2018)

Universidad Abierta Interamericana

Associate's Degree, International Relations and Affairs, International Relations and Affairs · (2014 - 2014)

Universidad Nacional del Litoral

Bachelor's Degree, Political Science, Political Science · (2008 - 2014)

Instituto Superior "César Vázquez"

Prof., Education, Education · (2000 - 2005)